DATABASE ENGINEER

Profile

 \hat{A} · Over 5 years of experience in Software Development, and over 3 years with OBIEE 11/10 \hat{A} ·

Â·Â Over 1.5 years experience with BI/XML Publisher

· Extensive experience in OBIEE Administration Tool, OBIEE Answers, OBIEE Interactive Dashboards, BI Publisher, Delivers and iBots within OBIEE suite

 $\hat{A} \cdot \hat{A}$ Experience with \hat{A} Data flow diagrams, Data dictionary, Database normalization theory techniques, Entity relation modeling \hat{A} and \hat{A} design techniques. Expertise in Client-Server application development using Oracle \hat{A} 11g/10g/9i/8i, PL/SQL,

SQL *PLUS,TOAD and SQL*LOADER

. Effectively made use of Table Functions, Indexes, Table Partitioning, Collections, Analytical functions, Materialized Views, Query Re-Write and Transportable table spaces

. Strong experience in Data warehouse concepts, ETL.Good knowledge on logical and physical Data Modeling using normalizing Techniques.Created Tables, Views, Constraints, Index (B Tree, Bitmap and Function Based).

· Experienced in tuning Informatica Mappings, Sessions and SQL queries for better performance

· Designed Star schemas, Snowflake schemas for Data Marts and Data Warehouses

· Â Experience in shell scripting (pre-sessions and post-sessions commands)

Â: Expertise in debugging and optimizing the Oracle BI / OBIEE Dashboards / Reports and Informatica Mappings / Workflows

 \hat{A} · In-depth knowledge in formal Systems analysis design, implementation of Operational/Database systems, utilizing Oracle RDBMS Methodologies

Excellent problem solving, troubleshooting and decision-making skills.

Skills

- C, C++, C#, Java, J2EE
- Scripting Languages: JavaScript, JSP servlets, XML, HTML, Shell, Python, Ruby
- Java Technologies: J2SE1.3, J2EE 1.3, Servlets 2.3, JSP 1.2, EJB 2.0, JDBC, JMS
- SCM Tools: CVS, SVN, GIT, ClearCase, Mercurial, Perforce
- Build Tools: ANT, Maven, Make
- CI Tools: Jenkins/Hudson, Bamboo, AnthilPro, CruiseControl
- Bug Tracking Tools: Jira, Rally, Remedy, Bugzilla, ClearQuest
- Operating Systems: MS Windows XP/2000/NT/98, UNIX, Linux, MS DOS, Android, Mac
- Database: Oracle 10g and 8i/9i, MS SQL, DB2 7.2/8/1/8.2 Servers Apache,
- Tomcat, IBM JBoss, WebLogic, WebSphere
- Tools: MS Office Suite, Confluence

Professional Experience

Database Engineer

August 2012 to Current Rtx i1/4 Springfield, VA

 Coordinated with the front end design team to provide them with the necessary stored procedures and packages and the necessary insight into the data. Worked on A SQL*Loader A to load data from flat files obtained from various facilities every day. Created and modified several UNIX shellScripts according to the changing needs of the project and client requirements. Wrote Unix Shell Scripts to process the files on daily basis like renaming the file, extracting date from the file, unzipping the file and remove the junk characters from the file before loading them into the base tables. Involved in the continuous enhancements and fixing of production problems. Generated server side PL/SQL scripts for data manipulation and validation and materialized views for remote instances. Developed PL/SQL triggersÄ andÄ master tablesÄ for automatic creation of primary keys. Created PL/SQLÄ stored procedures, functions and packagesÄ for moving the data from staging area to data mart. Created scripts to create A new tables, views, queries A for new enhancement in the application using TOAD. Created indexes on the tables for faster retrieval of the data to enhance database performance. Involved in data loading using PL/SQL and SQL*Loader calling UNIX scripts to download and manipulate files.Performed SQL and PL/SQL tuning and Application tuning using various tools like EXPLAIN PLAN, SQL*TRACE, TKPROF and AUTOTRACE. Extensively involved in using hints to direct the optimizer to choose an optimizer query execution plan. Used Bulk Collections for better performance and easy retrieval of data, by reducing context switching between SQL and PL/SQL engines. Created PL/SQL scripts to extract the data from the operational database into simple flat text files using UTL FILEpackage. Creation of database objects like tables, views, materialized views, procedures and packages using oracle tools like Toad, PL/SQL Developer and SQL* plus. Partitioned the fact tables and materialized views to enhance the performance. Extensively used bulk collection in PL/SQL objects for improving the performing. Created records, tables, collections (nested tables and arrays) for improving Query performance by reducing context switching. Used Pragma Autonomous Transaction to avoid mutating problem in database trigger. Extensively used the advanced features of PL/SQL like Records, Tables, Object types and Dynamic SQL. Handled errors using Exception Handling extensively for the ease of debugging and displaying the error messages in the application.

Devops/AWS Engineer

November 2010 to August 2012 JP Morgan Chase il/4 City, STATE

- Responsible for managing infrastructure provisioning (S3, ELB, EC2, RDS, Route 53, IAM, security groups CIDR's, VCP, NAT) and deployment via SCALR and EC2 Installs with CentOS, Ubuntu and RHEL 6 and Scientific Linux.
- Automate Deployment using configuration Management tool like puppet to provision amazon AWS Instances to enable continuous Deployments.

- Involved in maintaining the user accounts (IAM), RDS, Route 53, VPC, RDB, DynamoDB, SES, SQS and SNS services in AWS cloud.
- Worked on Autoscaling, Cloudwatch(monitoring), AWS Elastic Beanstalk(app deployments), Amazon S3(storage) and Amazon EBS(persistent disk storage).
- Wrote and maintained build scripts for E2Open cloud platform SaaS applications modules like supplier services and admin portal using Mayern
- Migrating the application from WebLogic to JBoss.
- Configured connection pools.
- JMS Queues and Converted data sources from weblogic to Jboss.
- Upgraded the full web and application hosting platform for JBoss and Apache.
- Installed, Configured, Integrated, tuned and administered WebLogic 10.x/11g/12c and related components.
- Managed and Monitored JVM Performance by adjusting WebLogic heap size and garbage collection parameters.
- Backing up the SOA Applications and upgraded Oracle Fusion Middleware SOA Suite 10g to 11g.
- Implemented a Continuous Delivery pipeline with Docker, Jenkins and GitHub and AWS AMI's, Whenever a new github branch gets
 started, Jenkins, our Continuous Integration server, automatically attempts to build a new Docker container from it, The Docker container
 leverages Linux containers and has the AMI baked in.
- Converted our staging and Production environment from a handful AMI's to a single bare metal host running Docker.
- Configured and administered JDBC, JMS, Work Managers and SNMP in WebLogic Server and JBoss Application Server Wrote Shell scripts to apply the Integration label to all the files which needed manual labeling.
- Gathered all the stakeholder approvals and necessary signoffs while acting as a release manager for two development teams.
- Created analytical matrices reports and dashboards for release services based on Rally tickets.
- Experience working directly with external partners for scheduling and coordination application teams (LGS, ICMP, enterprise), TIS support teams (UNIX, middleware, patching, network, storage) Gathered all the stakeholder approvals and necessary signoffs while acting as a release manager for two development teams.
- Created analytical matrices reports and dashboards for release services based on Rally tickets.
- Created a complete release process doc, which explained all the steps involved in the release process.
- Updated the Database Tables running the Database Scripts.
- Environment: Java/J2EE, Maven, Subversion, Git, GitHub, UNIX, Rally, Shell, Artifactory, Jenkins/Hudson, Python, JBoss, WebSphere, Confluence, Linux, MYSQL.

Sr. Build and Release Engineer/Dev Ops Engineer

July 2008 to November 2010 Gartner Corp i1/4 City, STATE

- Created and deployed builds to different environments based on requests.
- Converted and automated builds using Maven and Make.
- Scheduled automated nightly builds using Jenkins.
- Helped developers and other project teams to set views and environments.
- Created and applied Baselines and Labels for each Build Artifacts.
- Created UCM Projects, Development and Integration views for Development and Integration Streams.
- Created and maintained documentation of build and release processes and application configuration to comply with audit requirements and Industry best practices.
- Produced release notes and other build-related documentation.
- Deployed a small set of ClearCase Triggers to enforce fundamental custom policies and also to guide, monitor and control development activities.
- Created Pre-operation and Post-operation triggers in UCM.
- Developed scripts using BASH and BATCH files for Automation of Activities and builds.
- Worked closely with Web Administrators to setup an automated deployment for SharePoint applications using SVN and Git Tools.
- Provided level one support for build troubleshooting and production issues.
- Installed Weblogic servers, configured domains across Prod and Non Prod environments for deploying retail applications.
- Installed and Configured Apache to Weblogic Plug-in.
- Installation and configuration of Oracle Fusion Middleware SOA.
- Managing the SOA instances.
- Deploying SOA applications.
- Extensively used WLST (WebLogic Scripting Tool), Perl, Python and UNIX Shell Scripts to monitor and manage WebLogic server instances and domains and for auto deployment processes.
- Setting up the cluster environment for Weblogic Server integrated with multiple workflows.
- 24/7 on-call support for emergency site maintenance and immediate build and install requests.
- Worked with the automated scripts for the Build and Deployment of the applications.
- Monitored and administered the automated build and continuous integration process to ensure correct build execution, and facilitate resolution of build failures.
- Maintained configuration files for each application for the purpose of build and install on different environments.
- Created the build instructions does and install (deploy) instructions does for each application for different environments.
- Performed merges between different branches, and resolved all merge conflicts successfully by working with development teams.
- Added different queries to query work items.
- Implemented, maintained, and troubleshot software build environments.
- Experience working directly with external partners for scheduling and coordination application teams (LGS, ICMP, enterprise), TIS support

teams (UNIX, middleware, patching, network, storage) Defined, implemented, and documented software deployment strategies and installation procedures.

- Performed Baseless merges.
- Environment: Solaris, UNIX, Java/J2EE, Eclipse 3.20, Make, Maven, Python, Subversion, GIT, WebSphere Application Server (WAS), Jenkins/Hudson, ClearCase 7.0, Jenkins, Crucible, Remedy, BASH.

Build and Release Engineer/Dev Ops Engineer

January 2007 to July 2008 Bank Of America i1/4 STATE

- Responsibilities Used Perforce for the purpose of Software Configuration management and maintaining the versions of the Symantec's Website Code.
- Coordinating the resources by working closely with Project Manager's for the release and Project Manager for all the Operational Projects.
- Carried Deployments and builds on various environments.
- Wrote ANT Scripts to automate the build process.
- Created the Deployment notes along with the Local SCM team and released the Deployment Instruction to application support.
- Coordinated with IT groups on the release timings to ensure systems are ready for code to be deployed.
- Managed source code, software builds, software versioning, and defect tracking on all software maintenance tasks and projects.
- Maintained release plan, managed release content, communicated release status and analyzed functional and technical dependencies among projects and maintenance of releases.
- Implemented UCM solution for Unity Project.
- Participated to upgrade the ClearCase server with patches and new ClearCase licenses.
- Planned and wrote Project's CM Plans and process.
- Helped CC Admin and involved in Administrator Activities.
- Performed Builds for various Environments such as QA, Integration, UAT and Productions Environment.
- Documented the deployment process (Migration Doc) of code to production on an Excel Sheet.
- Worked on ETL tools like Informatica Power Center and reporting tools like Business Objects.
- Moved the Informatica Mappings, Sessions and Business Objects universe and reports from one environment to other environment.
- Work directly with Project Managers to establish and create & design therelease plan.
- Identify and coordinate deployment of appropriate modules to various test environments and production environments.
- Work closely with developers to pinpoint and provide early warnings of common build failure.
- Pro-actively Installed and configured GIT and Gerrit Experience working directly with external partners for scheduling and coordination
 application teams (LGS, ICMP, enterprise), TIS support teams (UNIX, middleware, patching, network, storage) Responsible for GIT and
 Gerritadministration.
- Environment: Java, J2EE, Ant, Maven, Anthilpro, ClearCase, Shell, Html, Oracle 8.x/10.x, Solaris, Servlets, Remedy, JDK 1.4.2.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Technology: Electrical and Control Engineering Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Electrical and Control Engineering JNT University), Kukatpally, Hyderabad, Andhra praadesh

.NET, ANT, Apache, Automate, Automation, backup, BASH, Business Objects, C, C++, ClearCase, ClearCase 7.0, Configuration management, content, CVS, Database, Delivery, documentation, Eclipse 3.20, EJB 2.0, ETL, XML, functional, HTML, IBM, DB2 7.2, Informatica, Instruction, J2EE, J2EE 1.3, Java, JMS, JSP, JSP 1.2, JavaScript, JBoss, JDBC, jQuery, Linux, notes, Mac, Managing, meetings, C#, Excel, MS Office Suite, Office, SharePoint, 2000, 98, NT, MS Windows XP, Middleware, Migration, MS DOS, MYSQL, enterprise, network, networks, Operating Systems, Oracle 8.x, Oracle, pen, Perl Scripting, Perl, policies, processes, Python, QA, reporting, retail, scheduling, Scientific, Servers, Servlets 2.3, Servlets, Shell, Scripts, Shell scripts, Shell scripting, Scripting, SNMP, Solaris, MS SQL, SSL, Symantec, Tables, Tomcat, troubleshooting, UNIX, UNIX Shell Scripts, upgrade, Visual Studio, Website, WebLogic, WebSphere